Amen.
We want to read a scripture. Uh we're
reading from 2 Timothy chapter 1 verse 6
to 14.
And this passage will be the passage for
us this year in 2 Timothy chapter 1
actually verse 1-4 but we are reading
verse 6 to 14. The Bible says this,
"For this reason
I remind you to fan into flame the gift
of God which is in you through the
laying on of my hands.
For the spirit God gave us,
not he will give us."
For the spirit God gave us does not make
us timid but gives us power, love and
self discipline.
So do not be ashamed of the testimony
about our Lord or me his prisoner.
Rather join with me in suffering for the
gospel.
By the power of God
he has saved us and called us to a holy
life. Not because of anything we have
done, but because of his own purpose and
grace.
This grace was given us in Christ, Jesus
before the beginning of time. But it has
now been revealed through the appearing
of our savior Christ Jesus who has
destroyed death and has brought life and
immortality to light through the gospel.
Out of this gospel, I was appointed a
herald and an apostle and a teacher.
That is why I'm suffering as I am. Yet
this is no cause for shame because I
know whom I have believed. I know whom I
have believed and I'm convinced that he
is able to guard what I have entrusted
to him until that day.
What you heard from me, keep as the
pattern of sound teaching with faith and
love in Christ Jesus.
Guard the good deposit
that was entrusted to you. Guard it with
the help of the Holy Spirit who lives in
us. This is God's word. God's people say
it. Amen. Please be seated in God's
presence.
Uh take a moment and congratulate your
neighbor for coming to church today.
Amen.
I know for some husbands they don't need
to be congratulated. They were dragged
to church.
Um and they were told you better show
up. But whichever way you are here.
Amen. We want to also welcome those
watching us online and wherever you are,
we believe that God has a word for us.
So shall we pray? Father, we take a
moment to pray and to believe that there
is a God in our midst
who reveals to us unarchable
things. And father Lord even in this
year when we are talking about uncommon
spiritled impartation Holy Spirit
download that revelation to us. Download
it so that we may understand the
purposes you have for us in 2025.
We thank you that you have given us life
even through the week regardless of the
challenges and the happenings that may
have taken place last week. But Lord, as
we start another week, we know that you
have something new before us. And we
believe that we are going to be
conquerors because you have already
declared us conquerors. So we thank you
for hearing our prayer. Bless this your
servant Holy Spirit. Give him that
anction to share this word today because
we have prayed in Jesus name. And gospel
say amen. Amen.
The theme for this year and I want to
just remind us is what
the year of the Lord's
and common spiritled
impartation.
The watch word for the year is the word
stretch.
In other words, this year God is asking
you to stretch your faith. He's asking
you to stretch your vision. Maybe you
are seeing till here. God is saying see
a bit farther. Hallelujah.
Really want to appreciate many of you
who are able to purchase and get these
two books. This is the the theme vision
and that is the planner and in that
planner we have a scripture for every
day of the year
broken down through the months the 12
months. So each verse talks about the
particular passage that we're dealing
with every month. And so today we unpack
this vision, open it up so that we may
understand what God has in store for us.
Look at your neighbor and tell your
neighbor it is an uncommon year.
Uh tell your neighbor it is uncommon.
And tell your neighbor, this year I'm
going to be uncommon. This year I'm
going to be Amen. Like I said last week,
we're going to be rare. No, we talk
about we are rare. Some of us have been
too common. So look at your neighbor and
tell your neighbor, I'm no longer a
potato.
No, potatoes are very common. Hello.
And uh they are cooked in many different
ways, Pastor Simon. They either mashed
chips,
strips, crisps, everything. Look at your
neighbor and tell your neighbor, "Potato
away.
I am a diamond in this year. I am a
diamond in this year. Tell your
neighbor, I'm rare. I'm rare. You see,
those are the things I was talking about
last week because indeed this is a rare
year. It is an uncommon year. It is a
spiritled year,
not man-led, but spiritled. And it's my
prayer that if you have not purchased
this book, get an opportunity to do so.
One of the things I've challenged the
pastors and pastor Sam I believe you got
that challenge the pastors of this
church that as you get that book
you have until 31st of January to finish
it
uh let me say
uh to pastor Igs
you have at 31st to finish it. Read it
through from page one to finish.
Hallelujah.
to the rest of us, take your time.
But I also want to challenge the
leadership, especially the deacons and
chall you're here and uh my brother,
you're here. You know sometimes it is
funny that sometimes we have a team
vision and the leadership catches up
with the team vision around April
and you wonder who is leading who
are the leaders leading the sheep or the
sheep leading the leaders. You can
imagine the sheep already have the book.
They're reading it. The leaders have no
idea what it is saying.
And I want to challenge the entire
deacon board
to read this book
and and during the pastor during the
deacons the board meeting I'll ask you.
Hello.
I'll ask you because
it is in essential that you know the
vision
that you catch the vision.
And Pastor Simon, when I say read, I
don't mean jump pages.
Leaders
read read and those who read are
leaders. But just to help some of our
membership, sometimes reading a book can
be very difficult. Now this book
um is divided in various chapters and so
there are certain specific places you
need to read.
For example, there's a page where you
need to read the passage for the year.
Another page has the verse. There's a
page which is just full of pictures.
The pictures here. Now, some of you
would be very excited to just read the
pictures.
Now, those are your pastors. Find out
what their ambitions for 2025 is all
about and pray for them. Bas
there places of where the the vision is
broken down. Then there's a place where
we call the the word study where we have
what we call uncommon. I I I break down
what is uncommon. I break down the
spiritled. What is spiritledd? I break
down impartation. What is impartation?
I've done that homework for you. All I
want you to do is just read it.
Hallelujah.
And then there are declarations. Towards
the end there are declarations. But
inside there's a Bible study for every
month that helps you understand what
this theme is all about.
And so remember this, don't be like some
of us during secondary school when we
used to take a whole physics book and we
knew we could not read everything. So we
took it put it under the pillow and put
our head on the pillow and expected by
osmosis
what is inside would come to us.
The Bible says, "Seek and you shall
find. Knock and the door shall be open
unto you." This vision is not for some
strange people out there. It's for you.
It's for me. I have read through this
book several times and every time I read
it, it excites me. It blesses me. And it
is my prayer that you will connect.
You'll engage.
So look at your neighbor one more time
and tell them, "Foolishness out.
Wisdom in. Wisdom in. Hallelujah. Amen.
Write the vision down so that those who
read it may run with it. For the vision
is for an appointed time. Though it wait
for it, for it shall surely come to
pass.
This morning, as I talk about this,
unpacking this vision, I want to talk
about three things. Number one, the
spirit of discovery. because we're
talking about being spiritled.
So I want to talk about the spirit of
discovery and secondly the spirit of
understanding and thirdly the spirit of
possibilities.
Number one the spirit of what? Discovery
secondly
the spirit of understanding and third
the spirit of possibilities. Let me read
Jeremiah Jeremiah 29 11 um verse 11-13.
It's a very interesting verse. We know
it. But listen to what the Bible says.
Jeremiah 29 verse 11-13.
It says, "For I know the plans I have
for you, declares the Lord. Plans to
prosper you. Plans to prosper you,
prosper you." The Lord will prosper you
in 2025.
Plans to prosper you and not to harm
you. Plans to give you a hope and a
future. The Bible says in verse 12,
"Then you will call on me and come and
pray to me and I will listen to you. You
will seek me and find me when you seek
me with all what your heart." It talks
about seeking, seeking, seeking. And I
want to talk about the spirit of
discovery.
Pastor Simon, it is interesting in the
history books.
Who discovered the source of the river
Nile?
Now you you I know you're a science
person. So let me ask somebody else. Who
do you think did that?
Who discovered the source of revenile?
Huh?
Dr. Who?
Dr. Speak.
Beginning Simon McCovy.
Dr. Speak did that.
But Pastor Simon, it is interesting that
there were people when he came who were
living in Ginger.
They were on the source of the river
Nile.
They lived there. They knew that the
river starts here,
but their names have never been put in
history.
Somebody discovered Mount Kenya from all
the way from wherever they came from.
But there were people around Mount Kenya
all the years. But their names are not
in history.
Let me tell you this. The reason why I
speak his name went into history very
simple
is that he left his country and looked
for the uncommon
among the common.
Now
he looked for the uncommon among the
common. You know sometimes when we talk
about the uncommon vision we're talking
about we are wondering God is going to
do strange crazy things around us. But
let me tell you this God does the
uncommon in common places.
And you have to have the spirit of
discovery to be able to have this
because I'm telling you as believers we
have lost the spirit of discovery of
seeking of searching of finding out.
Some of us have been Christians for a
long time. When we got saved, let me
tell you this. We read the Bible like it
was something we had never read before
because we are discovering things. We
had a spirit of discovery. We were
looking for this. We were looking for
that and we were finding it. But through
the years we told ourselves, I know
everything in the Bible. We stopped
having the spirit of discovery. Now, the
Bible is not a very interesting book
because we have lost the spirit of
discovery. But let me tell you this,
being spiritled is having the spirit of
discovery, seeking and searching, uh
looking at a verse, looking at it again,
looking at it again. One person who had
that spirit of discovery was Joshua.
If you know Joshua, Joshua was somebody
who always looked for things. You know
somebody who has a spirit of discovery
is somebody who is inquisitive,
intentional
and interested.
That is a person who have the the spirit
of discovery.
Einstein, Albert Einstein, by the way,
Pastor Simon and Albert Einstein was in
school.
The teacher said that this boy has
a brain like a seieve.
A brain like a seieve.
Whatever you put in doesn't stay in a
talker.
Hello.
He says that Albert Einstein was very
troublesome in class. He got bored too
fast.
What they did not know is this Abraham
Albert Einstein the moment he saw the
teacher write an equation he already
knew the answer before the teacher
started calculating it.
So the rest of the time he was doing
those things, he was looking for other
things to do. He had a different mind.
He had a different spirit and he was
chucked out of that school.
And today we know who Albert Einstein is
and what he did because he had a spirit
of discovery.
Joshua had that spirit. And that is why
wherever Moses went, Joshua
went. He wanted to find out where is he
going? I'm going to the mountain. I'm
going with you.
Moses did not tell Joshua, follow me.
Joshua just had this desire to know, to
discover, to get to know new things. And
when Moses wanted to do something,
he asked Joshua to do it. Much later,
when Moses wanted to go spy the land, he
sent Joshua. And Joshua was one of the
people. He said, "Go spy the land."
There were 12 of them who went. And
while they went with their eyes,
remember we're talking about vision this
year. When they went, they needed to
have eyes to see what they needed to
see. 10 of the spies saw a land that was
beautiful. Grapes, good fruit. But one
of the things they saw was what?
Giants.
And it killed their spirit. Killed their
dream.
But Joshua, even though he saw the
giants, he saw that there's a God in
heaven who is going to bring every giant
down. I want to say that as we look into
this 2025, what are you seeing? Many of
us may start seeing giants in the land.
But I'm telling you, instead of seeing
giants in the land and seeing yourself
as a grasshopper,
begin to see yourself as the giant in
the land. You are the giant in the land.
You are the one who is going to bring
things down because you have a different
mind. You have this spirit of discovery.
The Holy Spirit is a spirit of
discovery. Let me read it for you. First
Corinthians chapter 2
verse 9. We keep reading this verse.
We'll keep reading it over and over
again. The Bible says this. 1
Corinthians chapter 2 verse9. However,
as it is as it is written, what no eye
has seen, what no ear has heard, and no
human mind has conceived, the things God
has prepared for those who love him. But
look at the next verse.
The things God has prepared for those
who love him. Verse 10, these are the
things God has revealed to us by who? By
his spirit. And then he said, the spirit
does what? Searches. The spirit is a
spirit of discovery. He searches all
things, even the deep things of God.
Hallelujah. Even the deep things of God.
That's why as you read this book, ask
yourself what what what did Ambrose mean
by this and what did he mean by that?
When you read the Bible, find out what
is God saying this? And then stop asking
questions that will not lead you
anywhere.
For example, where did Cain get his
wife?
You know how people ask those kinds of
questions?
Where did Cain
get his wife? By the way, let me ask
you, where do you think Cain got his
wife?
Yeah, you see, you don't have an answer.
So, so forget asking questions like
that. But those are interesting
questions because Adam got two children,
Cain and Abel. But that's all you have
in mind.
Then the thing the next thing you know
is that Cain kills who?
You see that's how you're thinking.
Adam lived for 900 years.
What do you think he was doing during
those 900 years?
He was being fruitful and multiplying.
The the other person that you remember
the Bible says is Seth. So the Bible is
not just writing everybody who was born.
He the Bible picks certain people
because he it has a certain purpose to
fulfill. So you have Cain, you have
Abel. Abel dies many years later Seth is
born but in between sisters are born.
So where did Kane get his wife?
among the sisters.
It was until Moses
came. Now remember Abraham Sarah was his
sister,
steps sister, whatever. But it was
during that time of Moses that God said
and gave a law
that a brother should not marry a
sister.
Hallelujah.
It is crazy that in in season like this
sometimes when you're going through
YouTube and all that you find a brother
has married a sister. You find a man has
married a man. Crazy things are
happening today. But let me tell you
this, have a spirit of discovery
and some of these questions will lose
meaning. Ask important questions and
you'll get important answers. Ask
foolish questions
and you'll get foolish answers.
Walk with foolish people
and you'll become
I'm telling you walk with wise walk with
wise people you become and I'm telling
you park key in 2025 has come to a place
of full of wisdom and you're going to
have wisdom in 2025.
So look at your neighbor and tell your
neighbor I see a lot of wisdom in you. I
see a lot of wisdom in you. Tell them I
hope you are seeing it yourself. Spirit
of discovery. Hallelujah. Tell your
neighbor, spirit of discovery. Spirit of
discovery. Joshua had that spirit of
discovery. He wanted to know more. He
wanted to do more. He wanted to conquer.
No wonder in Joshua chapter 1 verse
three. This is what the Bible says. God
now is speaking to Joshua because Joshua
Moses had left. And so God is speaking
to Joshua. The Bible says this in Joshua
1:3, "I will give you every place where
you set your foot as I promised Moses.
Your territory will extend from the
desert to Lebanon and from the great
river Euphrates, all the heated country
to the Mediterranean Sea in the west. No
one will be able to stand against you
all the days of your life as I was with
Moses. So I will be with you. I will
never leave you nor forsake you." God is
giving us the same promise in 2025. He
will not leave us. He will not forsake
us. No matter how many kinds of giants
are in this world, God is the greater
giant. And we are going to conquer in
Jesus name. Hallelujah. Uncommon.
Joshua was looking for the uncommon
in common places.
Hallelujah.
One time they went to Jericho and God
gave him an uncommon strategy and he
said just go around the city. Don't
don't talk. Just go around the city and
after seven days go around seven times.
You know God is going to give you some
amazing wisdom in 2025.
Amazing strategies,
very common
but releasing uncommon results in Jesus
name.
And that day Jericho came down. Jericho
came down.
And then Joshua thought Allah I can
bring her down every city just like
this. And the next city they attacked.
Which city was that?
I.
Now that's why artificial intelligence
started AI.
But now we're talking about I. He goes
to I a small town and they are defeated
so badly they don't know what to do.
Why? They did not consult God. They
forgot to discover and search God. Uh
let me tell you this. Some small
projects are going to defeat you just
because you did not seek God's wisdom.
Have a spirit of discovery.
Hallelujah. Have a spirit of discovery.
So then God gives him the strategy.
Joshua chapter 8. So let me go back to
Joshua chapter 8. The Bible says this,
Joshua 8, when Joshua realized, I need
to know God. I need to find God. And the
Bible says Joshua chapter 8, chapter 8
verse one, if I can get there.
Joshua 81, then the Lord said to Joshua,
and I pray that you'll allow God to
speak to you this year. Tell your
neighbor, spiritled. Spirit, the Lord
Then the Lord said to Joshua, "Do not be
afraid." That's one of the greatest
strategies that in this year don't be
afraid.
Do not be afraid. Do not be discouraged.
Take the whole army with you and go up
and attack I or for some of you Ai.
For I have delivered it into your hands
the king of I, his people, his city, and
his land. you shall do to I and its king
as you did to Jericho and its king
except that you may carry off their
plunder and livestock for yourselves. So
it gives him a different strategy
down those verses around verse 18. Let
me read that verse now. Verse 18,
Joshua 8:18.
The Bible says this.
Then the Lord said to Joshua, "Hold out
toward I the javelin that is in your
hand, for into your hand I will deliver
the city." So Joshua held out toward the
city, the javelin that was in his hand.
As soon as he did this, the men in the
ambush rose quickly from their position
and rushed forward. They entered the
city and captured it and quickly set it
on fire. The men of I looked back and
saw the smoke of the city rising up into
the sky, but they had no chance to
escape in any direction. The Israelites
who had been fleeing towards the
wilderness had turned back against their
pursuers. But when Joshua and all Israel
saw that the ambush had taken the city
and that smoke was going up from it,
they turned around and attacked the men
of eye. Those in the ambush also came
out of the city against them so that
they were caught in the middle with the
Israelites on both sides. Israel cut
down leaving them neither survivors nor
fugitives.
But they took the king of eye alive and
brought him to Joshua. And of course
later Joshua hanged him.
In other words, I was brought down. And
let me tell you this, there's something
that happened. Look at the next verse.
When Israel when every one of them had
been put to the sword, all the
Israelites returned to eye and killed
those who were in it. 12,000 men, women
fell that day. All the people of I fell
down. And let me tell you this, Pastor
Simon, Joshua never threw the javelin.
He just lifted it up. For some of you,
you don't have to use so much of your
work, so much of this, so much of that.
Just lift up your hand. Stretch your
hand to heaven and say, "God, you can
make it happen for me." Somebody better
give God a big hand. You can make it
happen for me.
Finding the uncommon in common places.
You know, Pastor Simon, if before I go
to the next statement,
when Jesus did uncommon things in the
Bible, he did them in common places.
For example, John chapter 2, where was
Jesus going?
John 2
to the wedding of Ka. He went to a
common place. But out of that common
place, uncommon things began to happen.
Let me tell you this. God is taking you
back into this world of common events
and common happenings. But God is taking
you there with a different spirit. A
spirit of what? Discovery.
Be a discoverer.
Search and you will find. Seek and
you'll get it. Because the Bible says,
"And you shall seek me and you shall
search me with all your heart and you
shall do what? You shall find me." But
very quickly connected to this
particular spirit, there's the spirit of
understanding. That's the next one. The
spirit of understanding. The Bible says
this in Proverbs chapter 4:7 talks about
wisdom there. But now it talks about
understanding. It says this in Proverbs
4:7. Wisdom and understanding. Let me
read that verse.
It says this. The beginning of wisdom is
this. Get wisdom. Though it cost all you
have, get what? Understanding.
Understanding is the ability to unlock
the treasury of heaven into your life.
Understanding.
Understanding is when you put the word
of God into action and pretty soon you
begin to understand how it operates.
The Bible says that God showed the
people of Israel his works.
But for Moses, he showed him his ways.
Many times we look to do this work. God
show us the shows your power. Show us
this. But sometimes we fail to ask God
show us why it happened. So that when we
know the way we can repeat the miracle
and it can happen again and again and
again.
Hallelujah.
Thomas Edison, you know, he he he tried
to put together this light bulb and he
used so many materials. He he he
experimented nearly a thousand times
failing and failing and failing and
failing until after 1,000 he managed to
make this thing work.
So some people say he failed a thousand
times but in reality he succeeded a
thousand times to find how things should
not work.
And then the last time he then found
because now he had a spirit of
understanding.
Hallelujah.
The first time for those who went to
driving to to a driving school. Hello.
You entered the car thinking you
understand how to drive
especially because you saw your father
driving the car
or your mother driving the car. So in
your brain you you you knew I can
understand but the day you went into
your driving school and your the driver
helped you drive.
You could not understand when to break,
when to accelerate, when to be between
the lanes. Some of us would hit the cab
this way and you're seeing it
and then you're holding on to the
steering wheel as if it will come out.
But as days went by, you relaxed because
you began to understand
how to drive.
Look at your neighbor and tell your
neighbor, "We need a spirit of
understanding."
And so, as we look for uncommon things,
as we trust God for these great things,
God is going to give you a spirit of
understanding. Let me go to Gideon.
Gideon was a guy whose brain had reached
a stage of being so devastated, he
stopped understanding the God of Israel.
The Medidianites had come and really
devastated them so badly until they
stopped believing that God was still a
God of miracles.
And I want to say in 2025, God is still
a God of miracles. God is still going to
come through for you. Pastor Simon, I
want to declare that in this year that
the sick will be healed
in strange ways,
in uncommon ways. And it's not because
we're going to
increase the volume of our prayer.
Hallelujah.
We are not going to make so much noises
and things like that. We'll begin to
understand how God operates and then we
shall just do that and see the the the
sick healed and raised.
And I know when I was unwell, many of
you prayed and prayed and prayed and God
answered prayer.
The one of the verses we have is Acts
chapter 4 verse uh 30. It says stretch
out your hand
to do what?
To heal. And I want to say in Jesus
name, if you came to this church today
and those watching us online,
if you are unwell, if you are sick, we
are declaring healing
upon you in Jesus name.
healing from the top of your head to the
tips of your toes. May the flood light
of God's presence just flow through you
in ways you cannot imagine.
You can pray and believe God in English
in your own vernacular but let me tell
you this, God is spirit and God can
touch you in ways you cannot imagine.
God can turn a situation around in ways
you cannot imagine. And so we are going
to tell the Lord to stretch his hand to
do what? To heal and to do signs and
wonders. And one of the things I kept
saying telling myself in the hospital, I
kept telling myself, I will be a sign
and a wonder. I'll be a sign and a
wonder. And I'm looking at you and
saying, you shall be a sign and a wonder
in your careers, in your platforms.
You'll be a sign and a wonder. So look
at your neighbor and tell your neighbor,
Pastor Ambrose is saying, "I will be a
sign and a wonder."
And now if you're sitting next to your
wife and she's not believing it, just
tell her, "Pastor Ambrose said, "I will
be a sign and a wonder
in 202."
Believe it. But you need to understand
and get your needed understanding. So
God comes to him in this cloud of
darkness and this is what God tells him.
Judges,
I'm reading Judges chapter 6 verse 12.
The Bible says this, God is speaking to
him. Judges,
when the angel of the Lord appeared to
Gideon, he said, "The Lord is with you."
And then God called him what?
Mighty warrior.
Gideon says what?
Pardon me. Instead of receiving the word
as it is, he says,
"Pardon me." I'm looking at you and
saying, "You are a sign and a wonder.
Pardon me.
You are a sign and a wonder." Believe
it. Take it. That's your portion.
Hallelujah. Just stretch your mind to
believe that I will be a sign and a
wonder. And he says, "Pardon me."
Because he he was not understanding what
God was saying. "Pardon me, my lord."
Gideon replied. And then he says this,
"But if the Lord is with us, why has all
this happened to us? Where are all the
miracles and wonders that our ancestors
told us about when they said, "Did not
the Lord bring us up out of Egypt? But
now the Lord has done what? abandoned us
and given us into the hands of the of
Midian. The Lord turned to him and said,
he did not argue with him. He just said,
go in the strength you have. There is
something you have.
Go with it. You have understanding. Go
in the strength you have and save Israel
out of Midian's hand. Am I not sending
you?
Pardon me.
You're still trying to pardon me, my
lord. Gideon replied,
"But how can I save Israel?
My clan is what?
The weakest in Manasse, and I am what?
I'm the least in my family." Now, this
year, be careful what you say after
these two words.
I am. That word I am, is such a powerful
word. And so, be careful what you say
after that.
Never say I am poor.
I am weak.
I don't have what it takes
because you have what it takes.
So God tells him, "The Lord answered, I
will be with
you, and you will strike down all the
media medianites, leaving none alive."
But if you read the rest of the story,
Pastor Simon, Gideon still gave tests to
God, because Gideon was beginning to
understand how God works.
By the time Gideon got an army, he got
an army of 32,000.
And God told him 32,000 are too many.
Bring them down.
It is not by the numbers we are going to
defeat the armies. It is by God
will defeat the armies. So he chad that
army until there were 300.
And then the weapons they were they used
were completely uncommon.
A jar and a torch of fire.
But you see, God will do uncommon things
for you this year.
And that day, Gideon defeated the
Midionites
because he began to understand how God
operates.
And I pray that in Jesus name, as we
unpack this vision, you're going to
understand how God operates. As you
search the scriptures for yourself, as
you understand what redemption is all
about, as you understand why Jesus came
and died and rose again, as you begin to
understand those things, let me tell you
this, you're going to have the spirit of
understanding. One person who had that
spirit of understanding was Daniel. The
Bible says this in Daniel 5:12 as I go
to the third part and then tie up this
message. The Bible says this.
He did this because Daniel who the king
called Betaza was found to have a keen
what? Mind
and knowledge and what? understanding
and also the ability to interpret
dreams,
explain riddles,
and solve difficult problems.
Call for Daniel and he will tell you
what the writing means. Verse 14 of that
chapter, it says this
14,
I have heard, now this is the queen
talking to her uh the king. I have heard
that the spirit of God is in you and you
have what?
Insight,
intelligence, and outstanding wisdom.
Look at your neighbor and tell your
neighbor, I have insight. I have
insight. Intelligence. Intelligence.
Outstanding wisdom. Outstanding wisdom.
Tell your neighbor, you thought I was
not intelligent.
Now know that I'm intelligent. I'm
intelligent. Why? Not because you
studied from four, went to uh high
school, went to university. No, the
spirit of God
is inside you.
Hallelujah. Spirit of God is inside you.
I keep telling you about my younger
brother. My young brother, one of the
most difficult things he experienced in
school is that he could not concentrate.
He could not study. He he his mind was
not there. The best periods in terms of
school uh schedule were this
break time, lunchtime and home time.
The moment he entered into class, his
brain just froze.
My mother beat him, tried to wake him
up, beat his fingers. The guy could not
concentrate. Nothing was happening.
Ambrose was on the other hand, he did
not need to be pushed. He just studied.
He got things well. And and my mother
kept asking, "You should be like your
brother Ambrose."
My brother is wondering, "I am not
Ambrose."
Hello.
Then he failed class 7. My father said
he's not going to pay school fees for
him.
My mother looked for those monies.
They happened to Changa themselves.
My brother went and found himself a
school. There was a school near Jamuri
High School called City High.
Hello. He went to that school. My
brother suddenly woke up. He told
himself, "I have to shift." Something
changed in him. How? I don't know. He
began to click and understand things. By
the time he was in form four, he passed
form four and went to a gakhan high
school
to do sciences, biology and chemistry.
My brother finished, he did not go to
the university. He got interested and he
went to Camry where my uncle was a
researcher there. And my brother spent
time washing test tubes and flasks and
reading the books he could find there.
One of the Japanese when it because it
was sponsored by the Japanese came and
looked at him and he said, "Young man,
you look to be very interested in these
books." He said, "Yes, I'm very
interested." He said, "Would you like to
study in Japan?"
"Oh, would you like to study in Japan?"
My brother went to Japan. The first
thing he studied was the language. My
brother can speak Japanese. Then he
studied whatever he was doing in biology
in research and finished. came back to
Camry. My brother is one of the people
who researches viruses in this country.
Ambrose does not know Japanese.
Unless I'm speaking in tongues, I have
no idea
what Japanese is. But let me tell you
this, inside every one of you is a
spirit of insight.
Give it a moment. Something will click.
something will open up and the
floodgates will be released. Some of
your children by grade seven they are
not catching anything
and you're wondering where they'll get.
Some of them are going to develop that
much much later. Some of your children
caught things at grade two
and that is their path. Ladies and
gentlemen,
may the spirit of God, the same spirit
was in Daniel be inside you. Because
that same spirit that Daniel had has not
changed. He's the same spirit
we have today.
Hallelujah.
God is good.
So finally, tell your neighbor the
spirit of possibilities. The spirit of
Tell your neighbor the spirit of
possibilities.
Tell your neighbor this year things are
going to be possible.
Ask your neighbor, do you have any
impossible things in your life?
If they say yes, tell them this year
they're going to become possible.
Amen. But how does it start? Number one,
have the spirit of discovery.
Have the spirit of understanding and the
spirit of possibilities will become a
reality. Let me read this verse which
you know Matthew 14:28.
The disciples are in the waters. They're
in a boat. They're being stressed.
Everything is not working for them. Then
Jesus appears and then Peter says,
"Lord,
if it is you," Peter replied, "tell me
to come to you on the water."
Then Peter got then Jesus said come only
one command Judy come.
Now, Pastor Simon, what do you think the
other 11 disciples were thinking about
what Peter was saying,
especially Thomas?
Because among 12 people, there is a
Peter
and there's a Thomas. just among your
friends. Peter was a person we call
forward forward
in
there when there are no possibilities.
So he tells Jesus by the way if it is
you come anywhere
let me come and Jesus said come.
Then Peter got down he did something got
down out of the boat and walked on the
water and came toward Jesus.
Look at the next verse. But when he saw
the wind,
he was afraid. Beginning to sink, cried
out, "Lord, save me." Immediately Jesus
reached out his hand and caught him,
"You of little faith." He said, "Why did
you doubt?" And when they climbed into
the boat, the wind died down. Can you
imagine the conversation that happened
when he came back into the boat?
Imagine what the disciples told him. Ah,
look how wet you are.
For sure he was wet. and everybody else
was dry. But all the dryers had never
walked on water.
Better you walk. If you sink and come
back, at least you tried.
Hallelujah.
This is the year where you're going to
walk on water,
where you're going to think solutions
and not problems.
Think solutions. When you're faced with
a problem, think solutions. There's this
lady in the Bible
as I prepare to close and I've been
saying I'm closing for some time,
but I want you to read that story. 2
Kings chapter 4. You know the lady, she
came to the man of God with a problem.
She could not see anywhere else. The
Bible says, "The wife of a man from the
company of the prophets, cried out to
Alicia,"
"Your servant, my husband, is dead, and
you know that he revered the Lord, but
now his creditor is coming to take my
two boys as his slaves."
Alicia replied to her, "How can I help
you? Tell me what do you have in your
house?
your servant has nothing there at all.
She was still thinking impossibilities.
She was thinking the problem instead of
the solution. So Elisha helped her to
see the solution because Elisha did not
have the the solution. The woman had the
solution herself.
So look at your neighbor and tell your
neighbor, you have your solution. You
have your solution. Amen. It says about
calibrating your mind, shifting your
mind. Kidogo, just shift it. Kidogo. He
says, "Your servant has nothing there at
all." She said, then she said, "Except
what?
A smaller
of olive oil." Licia says, "That is your
solution.
That is your solution. That is your
solution. And where is it in your house?
Where is it in your hands under your
control?"
Amen. Look at the next verse. Elisha
said, "Now give her the strategy. Go
around and ask all your neighbors for
empty jars. And don't ask for just a
few. Then go inside and shut the door
behind you and your sons. Pour oil into
all the jars. And as each is filled, put
it to one side." She left him, shut the
door behind her, and her sons, they
brought the jars to her. And she kept
pouring and pouring. When all the jars
were full, she said to her son, "Bring
me another one." But he replied,
"There's not a jar left." Then the oil
stopped flowing. Tell God, God does not
waste his miracles.
She went and told the man of God, he
said, "Go sell
the oil and pay your debts and you, your
sons can live on what is left."
B John. This lady came with a problem.
But when she began to think
possibilities,
she went home and the next day she
became the sole distributor of oil
in that city.
Sole distributor
because suddenly she started thinking in
solutions. She was also an entrepreneur
because how do you borrow all these
vessels from your neighbors? Some of
those neighbors are not very kind. And
guess what? It is those neighbors who
started paying for that. Well, let me
tell you this. You have a treasure in
your heart. You have a treasure in your
heart. You have a treasure in your
heart. I want you to stand on your feet
as I continue to say you have a treasure
in your heart. I'm saying you have a
treasure in your heart. I say you have a
miracle in your hands. You have a
miracle in your hands. I'm talking to
somebody. I'm saying step into the
waters. Step into the waters.
What waters? When the Lord tells you do
something,
do it.
Pastor Simon, you remember Jesus told
the people in Cana, fill these jars with
water.
Do the common, I will do the uncommon.
Hallelujah. Amen. One of the common
things you did today is you came to
church
and because you did the common, God will
do the uncommon.
I've given an assignment as I said
earlier to the pastors.
Get this theme vision. Of course, I've
already given you copies as a
complimentary from me. Now, your work is
to do what? Read. When do you finish?
S I'm talking to you. When do you
finish?
By 31st of July.
Not the planner. Forget the planner.
Just this
chal. You had my assignment. Amen.
And don't come with excuses. But I've
been busy in ministry. I've been serving
the Lord. My friend, continue serving
the Lord. But finish.
reading this book so that I can have
people I can speak at the same level
because I've read this book so many
times. So I need people that I can talk
when I'm talking they know what I'm
talking about. They're not asking me
what does this mean?
God is good. So look at your neighbor
and tell your neighbor
Masolo, you know the assignment and we
know that God is taking you to places in
the sports industry.
But read the theme visual.
Are you glad you came? Yes.
God has not given us a spirit of fear
but a spirit of power,
love and a sound mind. And today we are
saying the spirit of discovery,
the spirit of understanding,
the spirit of possibilities.
Your doors have already been opened.
Just go through them.
And like I said this,
be inquisitive,
be intentional,
and be interested.
If you have those three things, you're
going to do great and mighty things. The
insights that are going to enter into
you will be amazing. For those watching
us online, may the Lord bless you, too.
And may you catch this vision and run
with it. The vision may t but it will
happen and it will come to pass.
[Music]
What?
Father in the name of Jesus such a joy
to be in God's presence
to have come to worship
to have come to pray
meet our friends
bring our family and children among us
and Lord we al also pray for our
children and especially our youth and
our children as they start their
services next Sunday we bless them that
the weeks they have been with us they
have been a great blessing
father we thank you again for parents as
their children go back to school as do
they go through those hustles and
bustles that father the spirit of
discovery the spirit of understanding
and the spirit of possibilities will be
upon them and upon their children. And
indeed they shall see the uncommon
things in common places and their names
will go into the history books of
eternity that they stepped out and they
made a difference. So father as we are
released this morning release us with
your love and with your care and may the
grace of God really abound in our lives.
And father, we thank you that indeed
that will happen. In the name of the
Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit,
God's people said, "Amen." Let's give
God a big hand. Amen.
Amen.
Let me command a blessing upon us as we
prepare to live at this time. Father, in
the name that is above every name, I
decree and declare this blessing upon
God's people. And I say, may the Lord
bless you. May the Lord make his face to
shine upon you. May the Lord be gracious
to you. May the Lord do you good this
day and in the days to come. Your Monday
is blessed. Amen. Your Tuesday is
blessed. Your Wednesday is blessed.
Amen. Your Thursday is blessed. Amen.
Your Friday is blessed. Amen. Your
Saturday is blessed. Sunday, you better
come back with a testimony because it
shall happen in Jesus name. shall happen
in Jesus name. shall happen in Jesus
name.
Now look at your neighbor. As you look
at your neighbor, tell them you need the
team vision book.
And then you need to read it.
Amen.
Look at your neighbor. Tell your
neighbor, surely goodness surely
goodness and mercy and mercy shall
follow you shall follow you all the days
of your life. all the days of your life.
And you shall dwell in the house of the
Lord. and shall
forever forever and ever and ever and
there's nothing the devil can do about
it.
And now may the grace of our Lord Jesus
Christ and the love of God and the
fellowship of the Holy Spirit be with us
now and forever more. Amen. Shalom.